<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Respond:Recover</title><link>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Respond:Recover</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 20:44:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gfraser.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Principles For Data Recovery</title><link>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/posts/principles_for_data_recovery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 18:34:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/posts/principles_for_data_recovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data Recovery is a complex topic to manage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recovery Point Objectives are defined by business teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not all organisations are convinced that there is a reasonable need to mitigate complex data issues post an extreme disruption such as a cyber attack, this can be evidenced in the following paper created as a joint exercise between SIFMA and Protiviti:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Protiviti &lt;a href="https://www.protiviti.com/gl-en/insights-paper/principles-for-data-recovery-severe-cyber-scenario">https://www.protiviti.com/gl-en/insights-paper/principles-for-data-recovery-severe-cyber-scenario&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code class="language-mermaid" data-lang="mermaid">sequenceDiagram
participant User
participant IT
participant Security
participant Backup
participant Service
User-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;IT: Reports ransomware attack
IT-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Security: Confirms ransomware infection
Security-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;IT: Performs forensics analysis
IT-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Backup: Restores data from backup
Backup-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;IT: Confirms data restoration
IT-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Service: Restarts service
Service-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;IT: Confirms service availability
IT-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Security: Validates service integrity
Security-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;IT: Confirms service validation
IT-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;User: Informs user of service recovery
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Cloud Disaster Recovery</title><link>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/posts/cloud-dr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 15:31:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/posts/cloud-dr/</guid><description>&lt;p>Disaster Recovery in the Cloud&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A guide for the selection of disaster recovery strategies when deploying applications in cloud environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The availability and fast provisioning capabilities of external cloud providers has led to a desire to use these services for the development and hosting of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This paper outlines the acceptable practices for the utilisation of these environments to retain policy compliance. It does not cover Security &amp;amp; Data protection requirements, nor does it cover low level strategies or solutions to meet Resilience requirements which will be expanded on in a later paper.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UK Operational Resilience Regulations</title><link>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/posts/regulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 12:39:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/posts/regulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.gfraser.co.uk/2021/03/29/uk-banking-regulators-publish-final-operational-resilience-policy/">UK Banking Regulators publish final Operational Resilience Policy&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having spent a fair chunk of my time over the last two years on both direct feedback on Operational Resilience and working collaboratively with peers on some of the implementation standards, it&amp;rsquo;s pleasing to see the influence that work has had on the final policies. Analysis to come later, but the links are here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/-/media/boe/files/prudential-regulation/statement-of-policy/2021/operational-resilience-march-2021.pdf">Statement of Policy&lt;/a> – Outlines where the Operational Resilience Policy sits within the context of Governance, Operational Risk, Business Continuity and Outsourcing policies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 21:02:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gfraser.co.uk/pages/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m George Fraser, an Operational Resilience Specialist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m currently Group Head of Operational Resilience Frameworks and SME for a Globally Systemic Bank. I also support the Scottish Government and sit on their National Cyber Resilience Advisory Board.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since 2006 I’ve been working to improve resilience within the financial services sector, helping to ensure that large banks meet their moral and societal expectations in the provision of banking services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been involved in large complex banking programmes, recovery from significant operational incidents, and the development of industry guidance, policies and frameworks related to resilience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>